Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and we're here talking about some special foods today.
我是Catherine，今天我们聊一些特别的食物。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to talk about seafood.
今天我们要聊聊海鲜。
So everything that comes from the sea that we eat.
就是所有来自大海、我们吃的东西。
That's right.
没错。
So we're in a restaurant and we're going to hear about the different options this restaurant
所以我们在一个餐厅里，会听到这家餐厅提供的不同选择。
offers.
提供的。
Let's take a listen to the dialogue.
我们来听一下这段对话。
This is such a nice restaurant.
这家餐厅真不错。
I feel so classy.
我感觉好有档次。
Yeah, it's a little bit pricey, but they serve the best seafood in town.
是啊，是有点贵，但他们供应镇上最好的海鲜。
May I take your order?
可以点餐了吗？
Yes, I would like some marinated grilled shrimp for starters and I'll also have the lobster.
好的，我想要一份腌烤虾作为开胃菜，再来一份龙虾。
Excellent choice, sir.
先生，好选择。
And for you, madam?
女士，您呢？
I would like the baked oysters and the seafood platter.
我想要烤牡蛎和海鲜拼盘。
Very good, madam.
好的，女士。
That seafood platter sounds good.
那个海鲜拼盘听起来不错。
Excuse me, what does the platter have?
请问，这个拼盘里有什么？
It's a great combination of clams, scallops, mussels, calamari and filet of salmon and
它是由蛤蜊、扇贝、贻贝、鱿鱼和三文鱼片组成的绝佳组合，还有
tuna.
金枪鱼。
It comes with a side of butter sauce and French fries.
配有一份黄油酱和薯条。
That sounds great.
听起来不错。
Cancel the lobster and give me one of the same, please.
取消龙虾，给我来一份同样的，谢谢。
Very well, sir.
好的，先生。
Anything to drink?
要喝点什么吗？
Can we get a bottle of your house white wine, please?
能给我们来一瓶你们店里的白葡萄酒吗？
Superb choice.
绝佳的选择。
I will be back shortly with the wine.
我马上把酒送过来。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So today we're going to take a look at a lot of vocab, so we're going to have two parts
今天我们要学习很多词汇，所以我们将分成两部分
of language takeaway and let's start with the first one.
语言点讲解，让我们从第一部分开始。
Language takeaway.
语言点讲解。
Now, in language takeaway part one today, we have a number of really important and useful
在今天的语言点讲解第一部分中，我们有一些非常重要且实用的
adjectives.
形容词。
The first one is classy.
第一个是“classy”（高档的）。
That's right.
没错。
So we're going to a nice restaurant and so you feel like you're in a classy place.
所以我们要去一家不错的餐厅，你会感觉自己身处一个高档的地方。
Now, a classy place is a nice place.
一个高档的地方就是好地方。
You might be expected to dress nicely.
你可能需要穿得正式一些。
It might be a little bit fancy.
它可能有点奢华。
Exactly.
没错。
So, classy is kind of a synonym of fancy or luxurious.
所以，“classy”有点像“fancy”或“luxurious”的同义词。
Right.
对。
So if you're going on a date with someone, it might be a good idea to go to a classy
所以如果你要和某人约会，去一个高档的
restaurant.
餐厅可能是个好主意。
That's right.
说得对。
But usually if a restaurant is classy, it also means that it's a little bit pricey.
但通常如果一家餐厅很高档，也意味着它有点贵。
Okay.
好的。
So something that is pricey is expensive and seafood is famous in America for being very
所以“pricey”就是昂贵的意思，而在美国，海鲜以非常
pricey.
昂贵而闻名。
That's right.
没错。
So pricey means that it's a little bit expensive.
所以“pricey”意味着有点贵。
Now going to the food that we're going to get today, we had a couple of different ways
现在说到我们今天要吃的食物，我们有几种不同的方式
of describing how the food was prepared.
来描述食物是如何准备的。
So for example, the first one is marinated grilled shrimp.
比如，第一种是腌烤虾。
All right.
好的。
Now, something that is marinated is covered in a sauce or a liquid before it's cooked.
所谓“腌制的”，就是在烹饪前用酱汁或液体浸泡。
All right.
好的。
So you can have maybe a regular steak, but you can also have a marinated steak, which
所以你可以点普通的牛排，也可以点腌制的牛排，这种
would be marinated in some kind of flavor like garlic or yogurt.
会用大蒜或酸奶之类的调料腌制。
That's right.
没错。
So usually you leave it in maybe some sauce like garlic sauce for a couple of hours or
通常你会把它放在像大蒜酱这样的酱汁里，腌几个小时或
a couple of minutes before you cook it.
几分钟，然后再烹饪。
Now when we cook it, there are different ways of cooking things.
说到烹饪，有不同的方式。
In this case, we're having grilled shrimp.
这里我们吃的是烤虾。
All right.
好的。
Now grilled is different from fried.
烤和炸是不同的。
Fried we do in a pan with some oil, but a grill, usually there's no pan, no oil.
炸是在锅里用油做，但烤通常不用锅，也不用油。
There's just a grill.
只有烤架。
So grill, grilled.
所以是烤架，烤的。
Grill is the tool that we use.
烤架是我们用的工具。
Grilled food tends to be quite healthy.
烤的食物通常比较健康。
There's very little oil.
油很少。
It's a bit more dry.
口感更干一些。
And oftentimes we do grilling outside because there's lots of smoke.
而且我们经常在外面烤，因为烟很大。
That's right.
没错。
Because usually you have like maybe a barbecue and you have some charcoal in there or some
因为通常你会有个烧烤架，里面放些木炭或者
wood and that's what you use to cook the food with.
木头，就是用来烹饪食物的东西。
Yeah.
是的。
And grilled food is very easy to notice because there are usually black lines on top and bottom.
烤制的食物很容易辨认，因为通常上下都有黑色的条纹。
That's from the grill.
那是烤架留下的。
That's right.
没错。
So we've eliminated grilled shrimp for starters.
所以我们先排除了烤虾作为开胃菜。
So what is a starter?
那么什么是开胃菜？
Well think about the word starter.
想想“开胃菜”这个词。
Start.
开始。
Now a starter is something you eat at the start of your meal, at the beginning.
开胃菜就是你在用餐开始时吃的东西，在开头。
You eat it before you eat the main course.
你在吃主菜之前吃它。
All right.
好的。
So it's also known as an appetizer.
所以它也被称为前菜。
That's right.
没错。
Starters and appetizers are the same thing.
开胃菜和前菜是一回事。
And these are small things you eat before you start to eat your main meal.
这些是你在开始吃主餐之前吃的小份食物。
So they're not very filling.
所以它们不会很填肚子。
Okay.
好的。
So yeah, it'll be something small like a soup or maybe like in this case some marinated
所以是的，它会是一些小份的东西，比如汤，或者像这里提到的腌制的
grilled shrimp.
烤虾。
Yes.
是的。
All right.
好的。
So great vocab there.
词汇很棒。
Why don't we review that part and we'll be back in a bit.
我们不如回顾一下那部分，一会儿再回来。
This is such a nice restaurant.
这家餐厅真不错。
I feel so classy.
我感觉很有档次。
Yeah.
是的。
It's a little bit pricey but they serve the best seafood in town.
有点贵，但他们是镇上最好的海鲜餐厅。
May I take your order?
可以点餐了吗？
Yes.
是的。
I would like some marinated grilled shrimp for starters and I'll also have the lobster.
我想要一些腌制的烤虾作为开胃菜，再来一份龙虾。
Excellent choice, sir.
好选择，先生。
And for you, madam?
您呢，女士？
I would like the baked oysters and the seafood platter.
我想要烤牡蛎和海鲜拼盘。
Very good, madam.
很好，女士。
That seafood platter sounds good.
那个海鲜拼盘听起来不错。
Excuse me, what does the platter have?
请问，拼盘里有什么？
It's a great combination of clams, scallops, mussels, calamari and filet of salmon and
这是一个很棒的组合，有蛤蜊、扇贝、贻贝、鱿鱼，还有三文鱼片和
tuna.
金枪鱼。
It comes with a side of butter sauce and French fries.
配有一份黄油酱和薯条。
That sounds great.
听起来很棒。
Cancel the lobster and give me one of the same, please.
取消龙虾，给我也来一份同样的吧。
Very well, sir.
好的，先生。
Anything to drink?
要喝点什么吗？
Can we get a bottle of your house white wine, please?
能给我们来一瓶你们的招牌白葡萄酒吗？
Superb choice.
绝佳选择。
I will be back shortly with the wine.
我马上回来上酒。
All right.
好的。
So now let's take a look at all the exquisite types of seafood that we have here on Language
那么现在让我们看看在“语言小贴士第二部分”中所有精致的海鲜种类。
Takeaway Part 2.
语言小贴士第二部分。
All right.
好的。
Now the first thing we have in Language Takeaway Part 2 is a very distinctive animal from the
现在“语言小贴士第二部分”中的第一个是一种非常独特的海洋动物。
ocean.
海洋。
It's bright red and it has two claws.
它鲜红色，有两个钳子。
Right.
对。
We're talking about a lobster.
我们说的是龙虾。
Now lobsters, you don't find everywhere.
龙虾不是到处都能找到的。
In fact, there are some parts of America where they're very famous for their lobster like
事实上，美国有些地方以龙虾闻名，比如
Maine.
缅因州。
Now these are animals that are hard on the outside and soft and white on the inside and
这些动物外壳坚硬，内部柔软白色，
they're quite difficult to eat.
而且吃起来相当费劲。
That's right.
没错。
So they look kind of like crabs because they also have the claws and everything but they're
所以它们看起来有点像螃蟹，因为也有钳子之类的，但它们
a lot longer, right?
长得多，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
They're round and a lobster is long and lobsters are also famous for one part, for their tails.
它们是圆的，而龙虾是长的，龙虾还以一部分闻名，就是它们的尾巴。
Right.
对。
The tails are full of meat.
尾巴里全是肉。
They're very delicate, very delicious.
它们非常细腻，非常美味。
Okay.
好的。
So we're having some lobster and we also ordered some baked oysters.
所以我们点了龙虾，还点了烤牡蛎。
Now oysters are another kind of thing that comes from the ocean.
牡蛎是另一种来自海洋的东西。
They come in a shell, all right?
它们有壳，对吧？
And you might hear about oysters because some people, some restaurants like to have an oyster
你可能听说过牡蛎，因为有些人、有些餐厅喜欢设牡蛎吧，
bar where they serve raw oysters over ice.
供应放在冰上的生牡蛎。
That's right.
没错。
So they look like big rocks basically and when you open them inside, you have meat.
所以它们基本上看起来像大石头，打开后里面是肉。
And actually I think you get pearls from oysters, right?
而且我觉得牡蛎里能产出珍珠，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So these two are special.
所以这两种很特别。
They have a nice relationship.
他们关系很好。
The pearl forms inside, it grows inside of the oyster.
珍珠在里面形成，它在牡蛎内部生长。
Very good.
很好。
So now we've taken a look at some oysters and talking about these things that have shells,
现在我们看了一些牡蛎，也聊了这些有壳的东西，
we also have clams.
我们还有蛤蜊。
Now while oysters are big and sometimes quite shiny, clams are smaller, usually white or
牡蛎很大，有时还很有光泽，而蛤蜊更小，通常是白色或
gray and they have lines on them and they're shells that you open up and you eat the meat
灰色，上面有纹路，它们是那种打开后吃里面肉的贝壳。
from inside.
没错。
Right.
对。
So I guess if you've ever been on the beach and you're collecting little seashells, usually
所以我想如果你去过海滩捡小贝壳，通常
those are kind of like clams.
那些有点像蛤蜊。
That's right.
没错。
They're quite small.
它们很小。
They can be about the size of an American quarter, 25 cents.
大概有美国25美分硬币那么大。
Okay.
好的。
So now in this seafood platter that we're ordering, we have clams, we have scallops.
所以在我们点的这份海鲜拼盘里，有蛤蜊、扇贝。
Ooh, scallops are one of my favorite kinds of seafood.
哦，扇贝是我最喜欢的海鲜之一。
They're quite soft and chewy and they're usually white.
它们很软、有嚼劲，通常是白色的。
Okay.
好的。
And then we have some mussels also.
然后我们还有一些贻贝。
Now mussels are much different looking.
现在，贻贝的样子很不一样。
They're also in shells, but they're long and the shells are black.
它们也带壳，但壳是长条形的，而且是黑色的。
That's right.
没错。
So clams are kind of small and round.
所以蛤蜊是那种小而圆的。
The oysters are pretty big and look like rocks.
牡蛎很大，看起来像石头。
Mussels on the other hand are long and black and when you open them inside, they're shiny
而贻贝则是长条形的、黑色的，打开后里面是亮闪闪的，
also.
也是。
They're orange on the inside or yellow and so they're quite interesting looking, but
里面是橙色或黄色的，所以看起来挺有趣的，但
they're also very famous for the French or Belgian rather, the Belgian dish, Moules Frites,
它们也因法国菜，或者更准确说是比利时菜——贻贝薯条而闻名，
which is a nice specialty.
这是一道很不错的地方特色菜。
All right.
好的。
And lastly, we are also having some calamari in this seafood platter.
最后，这份海鲜拼盘里还有一些炸鱿鱼圈。
Oh, this is another one of my favorites.
哦，这也是我的最爱之一。
Now calamari is a kind of food, but the animal is the squid.
炸鱿鱼圈是一种食物，但它的动物原型是鱿鱼。
Okay.
好的。
So why is it called calamari?
那为什么叫它 calamari 呢？
Well calamari, I believe, comes from the Italian word calamaro.
嗯，calamari，我觉得是来自意大利语 calamaro。
Calamari means that it's squid that's been cooked so that people can eat it.
Calamari 指的是经过烹饪、可以食用的鱿鱼。
Okay.
好的。
So basically calamari and squid are the same thing.
所以基本上 calamari 和 squid 是同一个东西。
They are the same animal, but calamari means that it's prepared to eat.
它们是同一种动物，但 calamari 指的是已经准备好食用的。
Yes.
是的。
And usually it's fried.
而且通常是油炸的。
So when squid is fried, it becomes hard, chewy.
所以鱿鱼油炸后会变得又硬又有嚼劲。
And that's what calamari tastes like.
这就是 calamari 的味道。
It's quite chewy.
相当有嚼劲。
All right.
好吧。
Great stuff.
太棒了。
Let's review everything one last time with this exquisite lesson.
让我们用这堂精彩的课最后一次复习所有内容。
This is such a nice restaurant.
这家餐厅真不错。
I feel so classy.
我感觉好有档次。
Yeah, it's a little bit pricey, but they serve the best seafood in town.
是啊，有点贵，但他们供应镇上最好的海鲜。
May I take your order?
可以点餐了吗？
Yes.
好的。
I would like some marinated grilled shrimp for starters and I'll also have the lobster.
我想要一些腌制的烤虾作为开胃菜，还要一份龙虾。
Excellent choice, sir.
先生，好选择。
And for you, madam?
女士，您呢？
I would like the baked oysters and the seafood platter.
我想要烤牡蛎和海鲜拼盘。
Very good, madam.
好的，女士。
That seafood platter sounds good.
那个海鲜拼盘听起来不错。
Excuse me, what does the platter have?
打扰一下，这个拼盘里有什么？
It's a great combination of clams, scallops, mussels, calamari, and filet of salmon and
它是由蛤蜊、扇贝、贻贝、鱿鱼、三文鱼片和
tuna.
金枪鱼组成的绝佳组合。
It comes with a side of butter sauce and French fries.
配有一份黄油酱和薯条。
That sounds great.
听起来不错。
Cancel the lobster and give me one of the same, please.
取消龙虾，给我来一份同样的，谢谢。
Very well, sir.
好的，先生。
Anything to drink?
要喝点什么吗？
Can we get a bottle of your house white wine, please?
能给我们来一瓶你们的招牌白葡萄酒吗？
Superb choice.
绝佳的选择。
I will be back shortly with the wine.
我马上回来拿酒。
All right, so seafood, we said, usually has the connotation of being a little bit pricey.
好吧，说到海鲜，通常它给人的印象是有点贵。
Why do you think that is?
你觉得这是为什么？
I think it's pricey because the best seafood doesn't come from seafood farms.
我觉得贵是因为最好的海鲜不是来自养殖场。
It comes from people who go in boats and they collect the seafood in nets.
而是来自那些乘船出海、用网捕捞的人。
And also, there are fewer and fewer places now in America where you can find this kind
而且，在美国，能吃到这种食物的地方越来越少了，
of food because some places have experienced overfishing.
因为有些地方经历了过度捕捞。
Too many people are trying to fish.
太多人试图捕鱼了。
And also, some places just don't have the right climate for certain animals.
而且，有些地方的气候也不适合某些动物生长。
Right.
没错。
So, for example, in the United States, you do have, well, the whole country is covered
所以，举个例子，在美国，确实有，嗯，整个国家都被覆盖了
in the West Coast by the Pacific Ocean.
西海岸被太平洋覆盖。
The East Coast, you have the Atlantic.
东海岸，有大西洋。
So obviously, you do have some coasts.
所以很明显，你确实有一些海岸线。
But if you're in the middle of the United States, it's probably hard to get seafood.
但如果你在美国中部，可能很难吃到海鲜。
So, I imagine it's very expensive.
所以，我想那会很贵。
It can be very, very expensive.
可能会非常非常贵。
So oftentimes, we get lake food.
所以很多时候，我们吃湖鲜。
It's different kind of fish, but we don't have lobsters.
那是不同种类的鱼，但我们没有龙虾。
But you'll find that in the West, you get very good salmon because Alaska in the Northwest
但你会发现，在西部，你能吃到很好的三文鱼，因为西北部的阿拉斯加
is very famous for salmon from the Pacific.
以太平洋三文鱼而闻名。
And in the East, it's very famous for lobster and crab, which are delicious.
而在东部，以龙虾和螃蟹闻名，这些都很美味。
Now, even though you have, it's famous for lobster and crab, it's still relatively expensive
现在，尽管它以龙虾和螃蟹闻名，但相对其他菜肴来说
compared to other dishes.
仍然比较贵。
Like for example, I think a lobster, how much would a lobster dinner cost?
比如，我觉得一只龙虾，一顿龙虾晚餐要多少钱？
A lobster dinner could cost you $150.
一顿龙虾晚餐可能要花你150美元。
Right.
对。
And you're getting almost the same amount of meat as maybe having a steak that would
而你得到的肉量几乎和一份可能20美元的牛排
be $20.
差不多。
Yeah, less meat.
是的，肉还更少。
But we have more cows than we have lobsters.
但我们的牛比龙虾多。
And also, lobsters are famous for being pretty expensive.
而且，龙虾以相当昂贵而闻名。
It's a very fancy meal to have lobsters.
吃龙虾是一顿非常高档的餐。
Exactly.
没错。
So, it's very interesting.
所以，这很有趣。
Some countries, for example, so it's very interesting, but some countries, seafood is
有些国家，比如，这很有趣，但有些国家，海鲜
very, very inexpensive.
非常非常便宜。
Some communities or some countries or communities that fish or have, for example, shrimp farms,
一些社区或国家，他们捕鱼或比如有养虾场，
it's very inexpensive.
海鲜就很便宜。
So, it's such a treat to be able to go there and have seafood all you want and not have
所以，能去那里尽情吃海鲜，而不用
to spend $300 on a meal.
为一顿饭花300美元，真是一种享受。
It is indeed.
确实如此。
And it's really nice to be able to get these big prawns, these big shrimp or lobsters
而且能吃到这些大对虾、大虾或龙虾，
and eat them without worrying about the price.
不用担心价格，真的很棒。
But I'm curious, in your country, do you have seafood?
但我很好奇，在你的国家，有海鲜吗？
And if so, what kind?
如果有，是什么种类？
Is it cheap?
便宜吗？
Is it expensive?
贵吗？
Is it pricey?
价格高吗？
Let us know.
告诉我们吧。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好了。
We'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里见你们。
And remember, practice guilty pleasure.
记住，练习“罪恶的快乐”。